Guide to the Morris Tyler Family Collection Of John James Audubon
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Autograph Collection, 1697-1887; Series VII; 0.6; (2 boxes)
  - WRITINGS
    - Heinrich, A. P. [Anthony Philip]: untitled song, 1820 (Box 13, Folder 657)
    - Lozier, Reverend J. Hogarth: "Hail to the Legions of the West", 1869 May 8 (Box 13, Folder 658)
    - Pollard, Josephine: "Jubilate Deo", n.d. (Box 13, Folder 659)
    - Silliman, Benjamin: untitled piece on chemical compounds, annotated "More copy of appendix" (Box 13, Folder 660)
  - OTHER DOCUMENTS
    - Ashley, Azariah[?]: provision return for the troops employed in the service of the state of Massachusetts under the command of Captain Ashley, 1787 Aug 7 (Box 14, Folder 661)
    - Aspinwall, Thomas: deposition of the crew of the Charles, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 662)
    - Corcoran, W. W.: receipt, 1829 Feb 21 (Box 14, Folder 663)
    - Dayton, Jonathan: loan note, state of New Jersey, originally presented to John Donavan, 1782, 1787 (Box 14, Folder 664)
    - Devens, Richard: receipt for beef from Tyrus Newton, 1776 May 2 (Box 14, Folder 665)
    - Duval, G.: Treasury Department circular, printed, 1807 Mar 25
      See: Oversize, Box 16, folder 732
    - Few, W. [William?]: receipt for payment of mortgage, 1807 May (Box 14, Folder 666)
    - Fish, Hamilton: passport, signed by Hamilton Fish, for William H. Arthur, 1874 Feb 25
      See: Oversize, Box 16, folder 733
    - Foot, Samuel A.: election proclamation, Connecticut, 1834 Jul 16 (Box 14, Folder 667)
    - Hart, John, J. [John?] Stevens, and Robert Smith: New Jersey Colonial banknote, 1776 Mar 25 (Box 14, Folder 668)
    - Jefferson, Thomas: act of Congress for the relief of Nathaniel Twining, signed by Jefferson as Secretary of State, 1790 Jan 4 (Box 14, Folder 669)
    - Kirkpatrick, Andrew and William Rossell: recommendation of Peter J. Clark for a license to practice law, 1816 Feb 29 (Box 14, Folder 670)
    - Livingston, William: certificate of appointment of John Hendry to the Board of Aldermen, 1784 Dec 21
      See: Oversize, Box 16, folder 734
    - Morris, George Pope: loan note, 1838 Aug 18 (Box 14, Folder 671)
    - Noyes, Edward F.: certificate, concerning the appointment of Henry W. Spencer as Commissioner for the State of Connecticut, 1881 Aug 4 (Box 14, Folder 672)
    - Parnell, Charles S.: House of Commons gallery pass for the Rev. Mr. Fanning, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 673)
    - Pickens, Andrew: state of South Carolina, proclamation concerning John W. Davis, 1817 Dec 12
      See: Oversize, Box 16, folder 735
    - Radcliff, ----: certificate of citizenship of Charles Dennison, 1828 May 29 (Box 14, Folder 674)
    - Sage, Russell: Chicago, Milwaukee and St. Paul Railroad Co. stock certificates, 1874 Aug 20 (Box 14, Folder 675)
    - Sparks, Jared: Harvard University, acknowledgement of gift, 1849 May 1 (Box 14, Folder 676)
    - Starke, John: demand for payment to be made to Edward Corwin, 1780 Jul 19 (Box 14, Folder 677)
    - Storer, Bellamy: notice of deposition, 1839 Jun 1 (Box 14, Folder 678)
    - Thomson, Charles: congressional resolution, extract from the minutes, 1781 Nov 12 (Box 14, Folder 679)
    - Trimble, James: deed for land sold to James Wilson, 1795 Aug 5
      See: Oversize, Box 17, folder 747
    - Trumbull, John: receipts for prints, 1789, 1791 (Box 14, Folder 680)
    - Warner, Jonathan: provision return, 1787 Feb 23 (Box 14, Folder 681)
    - Wolcott, Oliver: receipt, 1786 Sep 9 (Box 14, Folder 682)
    - Wolley, Richard: Scottish baronial court document, concerning land in the possession of Thomas and Mary Pilkington and John Ropier, 1697
      See: Oversize, Box 16, folder 736
    - Autographs, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 683)
      C. A. [Chester Alan] Arthur, John James Audubon, Lawrence Barrett, John Brougham, Francis James Child, Henry Colman, George Crooke, F. W. Farrar, Louis Antoine Godey, Samuel G. Goodrich, Edward Kerney[?], Sir Stafford Northcote, and unidentified
    - Notes, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 684)
    - Printed ephemera, without signatures, 1859-1916, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 685)
    - Receipts, unidentified signatures, 1833-71 (Box 14, Folder 686)
  - PRINTS
    See also: Scrapbook, Box 18, folder 748
    - Abot, E.: unidentified man, 1886[?], 1887[?] (Box 14, Folder 687)
      See also: Oversize, Box 16, folder 737
    - Aubry, Peter: Lovys Cardinal de la Valette, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 688)
    - Heckenaur, Leonhard: Benedict Winckles, n.d.
      See: Oversize, Box 16, folder 738
    - Maverick, Peter: Henry Clay, 1822
      See: Oversize, Box 16, folder 739
    - Perelle, A. D.: Veüe et Perspective du Palais des Thuilleries, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 689)
    - Rembrandt Harmenszoon van Rijn: reproduction of a work by Rembrandt (Box 14, Folder 690)
      See also: Oversize, Box 16, folder 740
    - Ritchie, A. H.: engraving of William B. Astor, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 691)
    - Robinson, H.: The Right Hon[orable] Earl of Durham, n.d.
      See: Oversize, Box 16, folder 741
    - Unidentified: untitled engraving, photo-mechanical reproduction, n.d.
      See: Oversize, Box 16, folder 742
    - Photograph: Yale Fence and Old Brick Row in 1877, 1901
      See: Oversize, Box 16, folder 743
- Oversize, 7; (4 boxes)
  Boxes 15-18 contain oversize material from Series I - VII. The material is listed in original series order. Box and folder numbers are included for each item as some of the material is housed in a slightly different order than listed.
  - AUDUBON FAMILY CORRESPONDENCE
    - Audubon, Lucy Green Bakewell, 1833-37 (Box 15, Folder 692)
    - Audubon, Victor Gifford, 1833-51, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 693-697)
  - AUDUBON CORRESPONDENCE WITH OTHERS
    - Bachman, John to JJA, 1838 (Box 15, Folder 698)
    - Grimshaw, James to VGA, 1847 Aug 31 (Box 15, Folder 699)
    - Harlan, Richard from JJA, 1834, 1835 (Box 15, Folder 700)
    - Malloy, E. A. from JJA, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 701)
    - Parkman, George
      - To JJA and LBA, 1835 (Box 15, Folder 702)
      - To VGA, 1835 Apr 25 (Box 15, Folder 703)
  - AUDUBON-RELATED CORRESPONDENCE
    - Letters of Introduction
      - Webster, Daniel, 1842 Jul 24 (Box 15, Folder 704)
  - WRITINGS
    - Writings of John James Audubon
      - Birds of America
        - Prospectus, holograph, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 705)
      - "My Seal" [photocopy], n.d. (Box 15, Folder 706)
      - Ornithological Biographies
        - Introduction to volume 3, drafts; and unidentified drafts, holograph (Box 15, Folder 707)
        - "Canvas back Duck," holograph, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 708)
        - "Great Northern Diver," holograph (Box 15, Folder 709)
        - "Hairy Woodpecker," holograph, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 710)
        - "The Mallard," holograph, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 711)
      - Viviparous Quadrupeds of North America
        - "Felis Onca...Jaguar", n.d. (Box 15, Folder 712)
        - "Georychus trimucronatus", n.d. (Box 15, Folder 713)
        - "Notes on the Skunk", n.d. (Box 15, Folder 714)
        - "Ovibos Moschatus...Musk Ox", n.d. (Box 15, Folder 715)
      - "The White Perch and its favorite Bait," holograph (Box 15, Folder 716)
    - Writings of Others
      - Audubon, Victor Gifford
        - Untitled, holograph: "It was a beautiful morning, the 16 Oct[obe]r, of the year 1832, that I stood on the deck of the small steamer 'Rufus King' ... ", n.d. (Box 15, Folder 717)
      - Sharpless, John T.
        - "Wild Swan. Cygnus Ferus," printed version, with annotations, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 718)
  - AUDUBON FAMILY PAPERS
    - Financial and Legal Papers
      - Charter securing a vessel for JJA's Labrador trip, 1833 Jun 5 (Box 16, Folder 719)
      - Contract [photocopy], 1806 (Box 16, Folder 720)
      - Insurance policy providing coverage for Birds of America drawings shipped to London, 1834 Jan 18 (Box 16, Folder 721)
      - Receipt by Robert Havell, 1829 Mar 30 (Box 16, Folder 722)
    - Maps and Plans
      - Entrance to Apalachicola Bay, drawn by N. L. Coste, 1834 (Box 16, Folder 723)
      - House plans, drawn by JWA, 1851 (Box 16, Folder 724)
      - "Map of country seat at Fort Washington," printed, 1855 (Box 17, Folder 744)
      - Minnie's Land
        - "Executors Sale of Valuable Real Estate & Water Rights...Estate of J. J. Audubon. Dec[ease]d to be sold at auction by Cole & Clinton, Auct[ionee]rs on Monday 13th Oct[obe]r 1851...," printed, with annotations (Box 17, Folder 745)
        - "Map of March 1872 surveyed by Mess. Michaels & Melendy", 1872 Mar (Box 16, Folder 725)
        - "Plan of Minnies Land the Property of the Late John James Audubon Esq.", 1874 Jun 12 (Box 16, Folder 726)
        - Untitled, showing 155th - 158th Street, in ink, signed "F. T. Vidal, City Surveyor", n.d. (Box 16, Folder 727)
      - Mouth of Mannatee River, drawn by N. L. Coste, 1834 (Box 16, Folder 728)
    - Other Papers
      - Passport: Audubon, Victor Gifford, 1836 (Box 16, Folder 729)
      - Passport: Robertson, John, 1828 (Box 16, Folder 730)
        Annotated in JJA's hand "Papers given me as a Curiousity by John Robertson Esq. 1828"
      - Royal Society, election list, printed, with annotations, 1830 (Box 17, Folder 746)
  - TYLER RESEARCH FILES
    - Transcripts
      - Correspondence (Box 16, Folder 731)
  - AUTOGRAPH COLLECTION
    - Scrapbook
      - Scrapbook, 1768-1870 (Box 18, Folder 748)
        Contents are listed below in series order. Scrapbook page numbers are given in parentheses.
        Audubon Correspondence with Others (to JJA unless otherwise noted):
        Abbott, Lawrence 1836 Sep 27 (19) Abert, J. J. 1831 Dec 29 (17) Bachman, John 1847 May 1 (7) Back, George to [JJA?] 1836 Apr 12 (117) Bewick, Thomas 1827 Apr 17 (111) Bowditch, N. I. 1850 Apr 12 (112) Children, J. G. [John George?] 1831 Jul (95) Dix, Dorothy L. 1840 Nov 24 (109) Morton, S. G. [Samuel George?] to VGA 1845 Dec 31 (86) Murray, C. A. [Charles Augustus?] 1844 May 3 (121) Musson, George from JJA 1832 Oct 11 (5) Rafinesque, C. S. 1833 Apr 6 (93) Redouté, [Pierre?] 1828 Oct 23 (92) Richardson, John 1836 Apr 8 (118) Ross, James[?] 1838 Jan 15 (119) Sedgwick, Adam 1829 Jan 28 (103)
        Audubon-Related Correspondence - Letters of Introduction:
        Augustus Frederick, Duke of Sussex 1831 Jul 21 (94) Brewster, David 1827 Mar 29 (110) Mitchell, Samuel L. to Dewitt Clinton 1824 Aug 11 (21) Roscoe, William to ---- Edgeworth 1826 Aug 8 (82) Webster, Daniel 1836 Sep (41) Wilson, John to ---- Ellerton n.d. (100)
        Other Audubon-Related Correspondence:
        McCown, John P. 1849 Nov 9 (35) Ord, George to S. G. Morton 1841[?] Dec 31 (87) United States. Joint Committee on the Library of Congress 1830 Mar 18 (107) Washington, John to J. C. Ross 1838 Jan 11 (116)
        Autograph Collection - Correspondence:
        Astor, John Jacob to George W. Smith 1836 Jun 16 (43) Curtis, George William to ---- Rice 1870 Aug 25 (39) Fay, Theodore S. 1836 Dec 3 (113) Gallatin, Albert to ---- White 1813 Jan 11 (106) Rush, Richard to Benjamin Austin 1812 Jan 10 (80) Thorburn, Grant to ---- Leffingwell 1862 Aug 19 (108) Webster, John W. to ---- Cleaveland 1837 Nov 12 (98)
        Autograph Collection - Other Documents:
        Dayton, Jonathan and Isaac Smith: note, partly printed, 1782 Aug 22 (96) Hornblower, Josiah: note, partly printed, 1782 Jul 21 (88) Lyman, Joseph: receipt, 1783 Apr 2 (104) Melvill[?], Thomas: certificate, partly printed, 1824 (115) Pringle, Robert: legal document, 1768 Dec 1 (114) Shepard, William: receipt, 1787 Jan 28 (105) Smith, Francis: order, 1771 Mar 25 (104)
        Autograph Collection - Prints (Photographs):
        Jefferson, Joseph, n.d. (44) Trollope, Anthony, n.d. (37) Wilde, Oscar, n.d. (37) Unidentified, n.d. (28)
    - Other Documents
      - Duval, G.: Treasury Department circular, printed, 1807 Mar 25 (Box 16, Folder 732)
      - Fish, Hamilton: passport, signed by Hamilton Fish, for William H. Arthur, 1874 Feb 25 (Box 16, Folder 733)
      - Livingston, William: certificate of appointment of John Hendry to the Board of Aldermen, 1784 Dec 21 (Box 16, Folder 734)
      - Pickens, Andrew: state of South Carolina, proclamation concerning John W. Davis, 1817 Dec 12 (Box 16, Folder 735)
      - Trimble, James: deed for land sold to James Wilson, 1795 Aug 5 (Box 17, Folder 747)
      - Wolley, Richard: Scottish baronial court document, concerning land in the possession of Thomas and Mary Pilkington and John Ropier, 1697 (Box 16, Folder 736)
    - Prints
      - Abot, E.[?]: unidentified man, 1887[?] (Box 16, Folder 737)
      - Heckenaur, Leonhard: Benedict Winckles, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 738)
      - Maverick, Peter: Henry Clay, 1822 (Box 16, Folder 739)
      - Rembrandt Harmenszoon van Rijn: photo- mechanical reproduction of Cottage with White Paling by Rembrandt (Box 16, Folder 740)
      - Robinson, H.: The Right Hon[orable] Earl of Durham, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 741)
      - Unidentified: untitled engraving, photo-mechanical reproduction, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 742)
      - Photograph: Yale Fence and Old Brick Row in 1877, 1901 (Box 16, Folder 743)
- Restricted Fragile Papers, 0.2; (1 box)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Box 19: ‡a Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
  - Box 4, folder 175 (Box 19, Folder 749)
  - Box 4, folder 176 (Box 19, Folder 750)
  - Box 4, folder 178 (Box 19, Folder 751)
  - Box 5, folder 215 (Box 19, Folder 752)
  - Box 5, folder 217 (Box 19, Folder 753)
  - Box 6, folder 322 (Box 19, Folder 754)
  - Box 13, folder 653 (Box 19, Folder 755)